<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parlons London</title>
    <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Parlons London</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 14:50:23 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parlonslondon.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>À propos de nous / About Us</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 14:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bavarder avec nous: installer l&amp;rsquo;appli &lt;a href=&#34;https://telegram.org/&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; puis &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/joinchat/QooAm1jMhWk7uXSdIFew8g&#34;&gt;devenir membre de notre groupe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Chat with us: install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://telegram.org/&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; app then &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/joinchat/QooAm1jMhWk7uXSdIFew8g&#34;&gt;join our group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour rejoindre notre liste de diffusion, envoyez un e-mail vierge à &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&#34;&gt;parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;To join our mailing list send a blank email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&#34;&gt;parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rejoignez-nous à notre groupe de &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/French-Conversation-in-London/&#34;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Join us on our Meetup group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prochaine réunion / Upcoming meeting</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/meeting/2021-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 14:50:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/meeting/2021-07-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notre prochaine réunion en ligne / &lt;em&gt;Our next online meeting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Heure / Time&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Samedi 2021-07-31 14h30 heure de l&amp;rsquo;Est&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Saturday 2021-07-31 02:30 PM Eastern&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;URL&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://westernuniversity.zoom.us/j/96489379313?pwd=SGJqdStYNUN5K2wzSEFxVmoxT3luUT09&#34;&gt;https://westernuniversity.zoom.us/j/96489379313?pwd=SGJqdStYNUN5K2wzSEFxVmoxT3luUT09&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or use &lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us/&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; meeting ID 964 8937 9313 password &amp;ldquo;ensemble&amp;rdquo; (No more Google Meet for the moment.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prochaine réunion / Upcoming meeting</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 14:50:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/reunion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notre prochaine réunion en ligne / &lt;em&gt;Our next online meeting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Heure / Time&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Samedi 2021-07-31 14h30 heure de l&amp;rsquo;Est&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Saturday 2021-07-31 02:30 PM Eastern&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;URL&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://westernuniversity.zoom.us/j/96489379313?pwd=SGJqdStYNUN5K2wzSEFxVmoxT3luUT09&#34;&gt;https://westernuniversity.zoom.us/j/96489379313?pwd=SGJqdStYNUN5K2wzSEFxVmoxT3luUT09&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or use &lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us/&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; meeting ID 964 8937 9313 password &amp;ldquo;ensemble&amp;rdquo; (No more Google Meet for the moment.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes de réunion / Meeting Notes</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/post/notes-2021-07-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/post/notes-2021-07-17/</guid>
      <description>17 personnes ont assisté.
Du vocabulaire interessante  le carnet de notes report card navetteur/euse commuter animal sounds dog: ouaf; cat: miaou un cabinet médical doctor’s office une dystopie dystopia sans concession “dark” (as in film or TV) coup de soleil sun burn coup de chaleur heat-stroke  Des Autres Choses Personnage principal dans LUPIN (tres bonne serie francaise sur Netflix): Omay Sy
N’oubliez pas Bryan Cranston!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duolingo Update for French Learners</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/post/duolingo-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 10:11:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/post/duolingo-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that &lt;a href=&#34;https://parlonslondon.ca/page/reunion&#34;&gt;our meeting&lt;/a&gt; is no longer listed on Duolingo. The meeting is still on, and everyone is welcome to join!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/ressources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 21:49:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/ressources/</guid>
      <description>We don&amp;rsquo;t teach French - we are deliberately a casual group just for conversation, there are no formal lessons and no homework or preparation is required. However here are some helpful links that our members recommend:
Learning  Duolingo - a website and smartphone app that teachs French and many other languages gradually, for free (or without ads for an annual fee) Memrise - a paid smartphone app that helps learn vocabulary Rosetta Stone - paid software with some similarities to Duolingo Free French course from TV5MONDE  Dictionaries  WordReference - free-to-use (apps also available) Linguee - free-to-use (apps also available)  Immersion: Watching and Listening  Radio-Canada podcasts - practice listening or just immerse yourself in the sounds 239 French Conversations on YouTube Language Learning with Netflix - an extension for the Chrome browser - if you have a Netflix subscription, it can show subtitles in your native language and another at the same time  News in French Canada  ICI Radio-Canada - Canada&amp;rsquo;s public broadcasting La Presse - independent, non-profit Québec news organisation  World  Courrier International - French language news from a variety of sources africanews - Pan-African news network Euronews - Pan-European news network France 24 - 24-hour international news TV station with a live feed, owned by the French Government (also available on YouTube) Radio France Internationale - French world public radio service  Online Conversation Groups  This group on Meetup Other French groups on Meetup - within 100km of London Duolingo Events has a lot of meetings, including in French  Local Information and Learning  Vivre en Français à London - list of French resources from the City of London, Ontario L&amp;rsquo;Action - London, Ontario area news in French Collège Boréal - offers French-as-a-Second-Language courses at their downtown campus in Citi Plaza Western Continuing Studies - offers French classes at their downtown Citi Plaza location Thames Valley District School Board - offer Core French and French Immersion programs for schoolkids The London, Ontario article on French-language Wikipedia  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
