<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parlons London</title>
    <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Parlons London</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 20:13:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parlonslondon.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>À propos de nous / About Us</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 14:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rejoignez-nous à notre groupe de &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.heylo.co/j7nz&#34;&gt;Heylo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Join us on our Heylo group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour rejoindre notre liste de diffusion, envoyez un e-mail vierge à &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&#34;&gt;parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;To join our mailing list send a blank email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&#34;&gt;parlonslondon+subscribe@groups.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Group from Meetup to Heylo</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/post/heylo-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 20:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/post/heylo-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are moving the group from Meetup to &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.heylo.co/j7nz&#34;&gt;Heylo&lt;/a&gt;. Heylo offers us the same facilities that we currently use on Meetup but is simpler to use and much better value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reunions</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/reunions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 20:26:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/reunions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Toutes nos rencontres sont annoncées ici / _All of our meetings are announced in our Heylo group, to join:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.heylo.co/j7nz&#34;&gt;https://link.heylo.co/j7nz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/ressources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 21:49:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parlonslondon.ca/page/ressources/</guid>
      <description>We don&amp;rsquo;t teach French - we are deliberately a casual group just for conversation, there are no formal lessons and no homework or preparation is required. However here are some helpful links that our members recommend:
Learning Duolingo - a website and smartphone app that teachs French and many other languages gradually, for free (or without ads for an annual fee) Memrise - a paid smartphone app that helps learn vocabulary Rosetta Stone - paid software with some similarities to Duolingo Free French course from TV5MONDE Dictionaries WordReference - free-to-use (apps also available) Linguee - free-to-use (apps also available) Immersion: Watching and Listening Radio-Canada balados (podcasts) - practice listening or just immerse yourself in the sounds 239 French Conversations on YouTube Language Reactor - an extension for the Chrome browser - if you have a Netflix subscription, it can show subtitles in your native language and another at the same time News in French London, Ontario L&amp;rsquo;Action - London, Ontario area news in French Canada ICI Radio-Canada - Canada&amp;rsquo;s public broadcasting La Presse - independent, non-profit Québec news organisation World Courrier International - French language news from a variety of sources africanews - Pan-African news network France 24 - 24-hour international news TV station with a live feed, owned by the French Government (also available on YouTube) Radio France Internationale - French world public radio service Conversation Groups This group on Heylo French Conversation Online on Heylo Other French groups on Meetup - in the vicinity of London Local Information and Learning Vivre en Français à London - list of French resources from the City of London, Ontario Collège Boréal - offers French-as-a-Second-Language classes at their downtown campus Western Continuing Studies - offers French classes Thames Valley District School Board - offer Core French and French Immersion programs for schoolkids The London, Ontario article on French-language Wikipedia </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
